[
    {
        "question": "Flowers which have single ovule in the ovary and are packed into inflorescence are usually pollinated by",
        "correct_answer": "Wind",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Reproduction"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of ecological pyramid would be obtained with the following data?\nSecondary consumer : 120 g\nPrimary consumer : 60 g\nPrimary producer : 10 g",
        "correct_answer": "Inverted pyramid of biomass",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Ecology and Environment"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the correct sequence for transport of sperm cells in male reproductive system.",
        "correct_answer": "Seminiferous tubules  Rete testis  Vasa efferentia  Epididymis  Vas deferens  Ejaculatory duct Urethra  Urethral meatus",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Reproduction"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following components provides sticky character to the bacterial cell?",
        "correct_answer": "Glycocalyx",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Cell Structure and Function"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following represents order of 'Horse'?",
        "correct_answer": "Perissodactyla",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Diversity in Living World"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following can be used as a bio control agent in the treatment of plant disease?",
        "correct_answer": "Trichoderma",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Not Available"
    },
    {
        "question": "The infectious stage of Plasmodium that enters the human body is",
        "correct_answer": "Sporozoites",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Diversity in Living World"
    },
    {
        "question": "The centriole undergoes duplication during:",
        "correct_answer": "S-phase",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Cell Structure and Function"
    },
    {
        "question": "If ‘8’ Drosophila  in a laboratory population of ‘80’ died during a week, the death rate in the population is",
        "correct_answer": "0.1",
        "user_answer": "0.1",
        "chapter": "Population Dynamics"
    },
    {
        "question": "At which stage of life the oogenesis process is initiated?",
        "correct_answer": "Embryonic development stage",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Reproduction"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the role of large bundle sheath cells found around the vascular bundles in C 4 plants?",
        "correct_answer": "To increase the number of chloroplast for the operation of Calvin cycle",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Plant Physiology"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nitrogenous waste is excreted in the form of pellet or paste by :",
        "correct_answer": "Pavo",
        "user_answer": "Hippocampus",
        "chapter": "Reproduction"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is common about Trypanosoma, Noctiluca, Monocystis and Giardia?",
        "correct_answer": "1) These are all unicellular protists",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Diversity in Living World"
    },
    {
        "question": "An important evidence in favour of organic evolution is the occurrence :",
        "correct_answer": "1) homologous and vestigial organs",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "genetics and evolution"
    },
    {
        "question": "The appearance of recombination nodules on homologous chromosomes during meiosis characterizes :",
        "correct_answer": "Sites at which crossing over occurs",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Cell Structure and Function"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following statements cannot be connected to Predation?",
        "correct_answer": "One of the species in predation gains benefit on the expense of the other.",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Ecology and Environment"
    },
    {
        "question": "The transverse section of a plant shows following anatomical features :",
        "correct_answer": "All features are related to monocotyledonous stems",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Structural Organization in Plants and Animals"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
        "correct_answer": "Ovules are not enclosed by ovary wall in gymnosperms",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Structural Organization in Plants and Animals"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an E. Coli strain i gene gets mutated and its product can not bind the inducer molecule. If growth medium is provided with lactose, what will be the outcome?",
        "correct_answer": "z, y, a genes will not be translated",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Genetics and Evolution"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following' ecological pyramids is generally inverted?",
        "correct_answer": "Pyramid of biomass in a sea",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Ecology"
    },
    {
        "question": "Osteoporosis is characterised by decreased bone mass and increased chance of fractures. Common cause of osteoporosis is increased levels of estrogen.",
        "correct_answer": "4",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Reproduction"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct set of statements:",
        "correct_answer": "2",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Structural Organization in Plants and Animals"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sickle  cell anaemia  has not been  eliminated  from the African  population  because  :",
        "correct_answer": "it provides  immunity  against  malaria",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Genetics and Evolution"
    },
    {
        "question": "Habitat loss and fragmentation, over exploitation, alien species invasion and co -extinction are causes for:",
        "correct_answer": "Biodiversity loss",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Diversity in Living World"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given below are two statements:  Statement I :  The release of sperms into the seminiferous tubules is called spermiation.  Statement II :  Spermiogenesis is the process of formation of sperms from spermatogonia.  In the light of the above statements, choose the most appropriate  answer from the options given below :  - 65 -  (1) Statement I  is correct but Statement II  is incorrect (2) Statement I  is incorrect but Statement II  is correct (3) Both Statement I  and Statement II  are correct (4) Both Statement I  and Statement II  are incorrect",
        "correct_answer": "Statement I  is correct but Statement II  is incorrect",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Reproduction"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bowman's glands are found in:",
        "correct_answer": "olfactory epithelium",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Structural Organization in Plants and Animals"
    },
    {
        "question": "The infectious stage of Plasmodium that enters the human body is",
        "correct_answer": "Sporozoites",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Not Available"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct set of statements:",
        "correct_answer": "(1) (b), (c), (d) and (e) Only",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Plant Anatomy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not the function of conducting part of respiratory system?",
        "correct_answer": "Provides surface for diffusion of O 2 and CO 2",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Respiratory System"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of placentation is seen in sweet pea?",
        "correct_answer": "Axile",
        "user_answer": "Not Answered",
        "chapter": "Not Available"
    }
]